FENCER ATTRIBUTES
（剑士）
PALADIN ATTRIBUTES
（圣骑士）
WIZARD ATTRIBUTES
（巫师）
ARCHER ATTRIBUTES
（射手）
Wow, look at all these posters!
好酷哦，贴满了海报
And the opening video is playing over there!
那边也有在播开场视频耶
Hey, Eita…
欸，瑛太
The menu is neat too.
菜单很有意思哦
Each of the dishes has a dungeon boss's name.
都是地下城BOSS的名字
Some of these bring back memories.
还有好怀旧的名字哦
You're too fast, Mr. Kamota.
鸭田先生的动作真快
Let me see!
让我看
The food actually looks good!
没想到看起来蛮好吃耶
-What'll you have? -Uh-oh…
-大家要吃什么？ -糟糕
I know Yamada and Princess Ruri,
我虽然认识山田和瑠璃姬
but who are the old man and the guy in glasses?
-这个大叔和眼镜男是谁？ -这叫灼热撒拉曼达咖喱耶，好怀念
More nostalgia!
真怀念
Do you like spicy foods, Eita?
瑛太，你喜欢吃辣吗？
If I had to choose…
真要说的话
I have more of a sweet-tooth!
我爱甜食
They're really enjoying themselves.
好像聊得超开心
Princess Ruri?
瑠璃姬
Who are those two?
那两位是谁？
They're guild members, right?
是公会成员，没错吧？
That's Mr. Kamota and Eita.
是鸭田先生和瑛太啊
Um, a little more information would be helpful.
可以再详细说明一下吗？
And another thing, my character
话说我的角色名称
isn't Princess Ruri.
又不是瑠璃姬
So the real question is, who are you?
我才想问，你是哪一位啊？
ORIGINAL STORY BY MASHIRO
（原作：Mashiro）
Um… "Who am I?"
那个…你问我是哪一位…
What's your deal?
你是怎样？
Why are you here at our guild meeting?
为什么你在我们公会的聚会？
Wait…
咦？
You are Princess Ruri, aren't you?
你是瑠璃姬没错吧？
-I keep telling you that I'm not. -But…
-我就说不是了 -可是…
I'll ask you again.
别说这个了
Who are you?
我才想问你是谁啊？
Wait a minute…
等一下
Where is Princess Ruri then?
那瑠璃姬在哪里？
-Princess Ruri! -Look--
-瑠璃姬… -我就说了…
Eita…
瑛太
Before ordering,
在点餐之前
shouldn't you introduce yourselves?
先自我介绍比较好吧
EVERYTHING LOOKS SO GOOD
（看起来真好吃）
Oh, you're right.
这么说也是
Sorry, Akane.
抱歉哦，Akane
Let's start over.
容我重新介绍一下
I'm Eita Sasaki, age 19.
我叫佐佐木瑛太，19岁
My hobby is online gaming.
兴趣是玩在线游戏
I play Princess Ruri online.
游戏里的角色是瑠璃姬哦
Pleased to meet you,
请多指教咯
Akane!
Akane
-Ne… -What's a nekama, you ask?
-网… -“网络人妖”是什么呢？
It refers to a man who uses
这是利用看不到面貌
the anonymity of social networks
无法判断身份的网络社会匿名性
to act as a woman online
男性假装成女性
or the engagement in such behavior.
塑造化身的人或行为
In fact, this term has been around
是在网络上佯装性别的简称
among PC users since before the spread of the Internet.
是早在拨接时代就出现的用词
You're a ne… ka…
网络人…
You've got the wrong idea.
误会大了哦
I'm merely a vessel for a muse
我只是一个小小齿轮
who has descended into our digital waters.
操作着降临在电子大海的女神
In other words, Princess Rui and I
所以我和瑠璃姬可说是同一人
are different entities but one and the same!
但也可以是不同人
Such a special state of affairs
这种特别的存在方式
should never be reduced to a cheap term like nekama.
不希望你随便用网络人妖一词称呼
It's not that simple.
其中的关系并没那么单纯
In the two-dimensional world, you could say
在二次元的世界，我和瑠璃姬
Princess Ruri and I are bound by fate.
正确来说算是命运共同体吧？
She is my goddess, my mother,
她是我的女神也是母亲和新娘
my wife, and my alter-ego.
也可以等于是分身
Whenever a man plays a female character,
大家一听到男生用女角
everyone starts shouting nekama this, nekama that,
就会嚷嚷着“网络人妖” 根本一点也不懂啊
-but they just don't understand. -Eita!
-我和瑠璃姬是更独特的关系 -瑛太
Compared to that…
虽然没什么人可以了解
-Ruri and I are more creative-- -Eita!
-总之我想说的是… -瑛太
RURI WAS A MAN…
（竟然是男的…）
You're not reading the room.
温度差很严重哦
I gave you my phone number
我还告诉你手机
and even told you about my breakup!
跟你商量失恋烦恼耶
Calm down, Akane.
Akane，你冷静点
There's no need to worry.
放心吧
You didn't tell me, you told Ruri.
和你谈心的人不是我，是瑠璃姬
Makes no sense!
莫名其妙
UH-OH…
（哎呀）
Um…
那个…
I'm Takeza Kamota.
我叫鸭田竹藏
My character
我的角色名称
is named Takezo.
是罗马拼音的“takezo”
Normally, I hunt for plunder in the dungeons,
平常都放置在地下城狩猎
so you've never met me in character.
我们在线上没碰过面吧
And this young lady is Runa.
这个女生是瑠奈
She's Eita's little sister
是瑛太的妹妹
and the model for Ruri.
也是瑠璃姬的参考人物
Making your little sister the model is creepy, isn't it?
把妹妹当作角色原型，够恶心吧？
And this is Akito Yamada.
然后他是山田秋斗
But you already know each other, right?
我记得你们已经认识了吧
What? What do you mean they know each other?
什么？已经认识是怎么回事？
What is he to you?
你们两人是怎样？
How could you possibly know each other?
为什么会认识？
That's um…
就是因为…
STARE
（瞪）
I'd rather not explain.
无法用一句话简单说明
It's a long story.
说来话长
I can explain!
很好说明啊
We merely met at an event!
只是在游戏活动上认识
In simple terms, that's it.
简单来说就是这样吧
It was hard not to notice, but…
话说，其实我有隐约发现到
THIS WOMAN… SUCH AN EYESORE…
（为什么？这女人真碍眼）
This girl really doesn't like me!
她果然超讨厌我的样子
Well…
不过…
I see.
原来如此
The people I met in the game
我在游戏中看到的
were Eita and Yamada.
其实是瑛太和山田啊
You were always flirting,
因为关系看起来很亲密
so I thought you were a couple!
我还以为你们是情侣
He's my neighborhood senpai.
他是我以前的学长
When he's in full character,
瑛太化身成瑠璃姬时
I have to play along.
我必须配合他才行
Yamada!
山田
FLIRTING X HIERARCHY ✓
（卿卿我我）
-Flirty, flirty… -Senpai's orders.
-卿卿我我… -这是学长命令
I see. That must be rough.
原来如此，真是辛苦
You told me before that you didn't have a girlfriend.
因为山田你说过自己没女友
I thought you might be lying.
我还以为你是在骗我
I wouldn't lie about something like that.
我不会在这种小事上骗人
Right… I'm glad.
也是，太好了
Huh?
奇怪？
Did I really just say that?
我刚才说了什么？
"You're glad"?
“太好了”？
You said, "You're glad."
你刚才说“太好了”？
So what exactly…
这句话…
are you glad about?
是指什么意思？
Does that mean…
难不成Akane…
you like Yamada or something?
你喜欢山田吗？
Th… that's not what--
不…不是…
I'm sorry, Akane.
抱歉哦，Akane
My little sister is very territorial
我妹的地盘意识很重
and going through a rebellious phase.
而且正处于叛逆期
She can be hard to deal with.
讲话总是特别冲啦
This won't do, Runa.
瑠奈，这样不行啦
-You can't talk like that to an older-- -No, it's fine!
-竟然对年长的大姐姐这么凶 -我没关系啦
At this rate, you'll never make it in grownup society.
等你出社会，这样会惹麻烦哦
Back off, Nekama.
网络人妖给我滚
I'm not a nekama! I'm just a romantic!
才不是网络人妖！这是浪漫！
-Stuff it. -Please don't fight!
-闭嘴 -不要吵架啊
So, um… food…
点餐…
Does everyone know what they want?
大家决定好了吗？
What'll it be for me?
要点什么呢？
That was a surprise.
吓我一跳
We should probably call for--
差不多该向店员…
Akane, are you okay?
Akane，你没事吧？
I'm so sorry. It slipped from my hand.
抱歉，我手滑了
Are you hurt? Let's call the staff.
有受伤吗？叫店员来吧
It's fine. I'll do it--
没事，我自己来…
It's too dangerous.
这样很危险
Better let the staff do it.
请店员处理吧
Right…
也…也是…
Excuse me!
抱歉
I'm afraid we broke a glass.
这边弄破杯子了
Oh, man…
糟糕
I wasn't…
该怎么说…
prepared for that.
吓死我了
What do I do?
怎么办？
I'm probably still blushing.
我现在的脸一定很红
Should I flee to the restroom?
是不是该逃去厕所一下？
Or would that be too obvious?
会不会很不自然？
Either way, I have to calm down.
但必须赶快冷静下来
Excuse me, everyone.
抱歉
I have a phone call.
我去打个电话
Sure.
好
What about food?
点餐呢？
We'll order for you.
我们可以帮你点
Please order without me.
你们先点吧
Thank goodness.
得救了
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
Uh, yeah.
没事
Um, I'll go pick some flowers.
抱歉，我也去摘花一下
You really are Princess Ruri.
是瑠璃姬啊
She's still glaring at me!
她还在瞪我
Enjoy your meal.
请慢用
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Are you okay now?
冷静下来了吗？
Yes. Sorry for the commotion.
是的，惊扰大家了
I'm just glad you're not hurt.
幸好你没有受伤
Thank you very much!
谢谢
Mr. Tamota is really nice!
鸭田先生真是好人
We heard that this would be your first offline meeting,
今天的聚会有首次参加的Akane
so we were really excited.
所以大家都很期待哦
No one told me and I'm not excited.
瑠奈没听说这件事，也不期待
Have you all known each other for a long time?
大家都认识很久了吗？
We knew one another from the previous game we played.
我们四人以前在其他游戏就认识
We started playing FOS after being invited by Eita.
因为瑛太的邀约，才开始玩FOS
Runa never logs in though. Once every three months, maybe--
只是瑠奈一直都不上线
I see.
原来如此
Other than me, everyone's acquainted.
除了我，大家都很熟了啊
Eita said there was a wonderful girl that we should all meet.
瑛太说今天想邀个很棒的女生加入
He was very insistent.
卯足了干劲哦
You're after my brother too?!
你这家伙，连我哥也想追？
I'm not "after" anyone!
我没有要追！
I thought you weren't a liar?
你不是不会骗人吗？
The phone call is definitely a lie.
打电话是骗人的嘛
What's up?
怎么了？
I just had a feeling
我总觉得…
that I should remove myself from her sight.
自己消失在她的视线内比较好
Don't come near me.
不要靠近我
She had that aura.
我看她散发出这种氛围
So that's your interpretation.
你是那样解读啊
I think what Runa said
我猜瑠奈的那番话
must have really upset her.
让她听得很不顺耳吧
Actually, I think she was just embarrassed.
我觉得Akane只是有点害羞哦
Embarrassed about what?
为什么要害羞？
Don't make me say it.
别逼我说出来啦
If you don't, I won't get it.
不说我哪知道？
You've always been like that.
你就是这样的人嘛
But whatever.
也好啦
Anyway, the real Akane turned out to be a beautiful older lady.
但没想到Akane 现实是个漂亮姐姐
You said she was just like her character,
你说和角色印象差不多
so I thought she would be more childish.
我还以为是更小孩子气的人
Yamada!
山田！
They're exactly alike.
我觉得超像啊
Come on, she's nothing like her character!
跟那个角色一点也不像吧？
You think?
是吗？
Most of the women on FOS have child-like looks.
毕竟FOS的女角都是幼女系
I can't tell one woman from another.
我分不出女生的长相差别
You'll never have a girlfriend
你就是老说这种话
if you keep talking like that.
才会连一个女友也交不到
Isn't it about time you stopped
拿我没女友当哏耍我
making fun of me for being single?
你差不多该腻了吧？
It used to be just for fun,
我以前只是耍着你玩
but these days, I'm sincerely worried.
但最近是真的担心你
Your lack of interest in women has gone to the extreme.
你对女生不关心的程度简直异常哦
You just felt sorry for me?
你在可怜我吗？
Is that true?
是这样吗？
Goodbye.
再见
Thank you very much!
谢谢光临
Thanks for coming, everyone!
那现在暂时解散
We have a guild battle tonight,
今晚还有公会战
so I'll see you all online!
晚上大家上线后再见咯
-Okay!
好
Sorry I can't walk you home, Akane!
Akane，很抱歉没办法送你回家
If only I didn't have to work tonight.
要是我晚点没打工就好了
You already got lost earlier.
刚才你还迷路了
Ruri's worried about you!
瑠璃好担心
I'll be fine.
我没事
What's the matter, Runa?
瑠奈，你怎么了？
You've got a scary look.
板着一张脸
I don't like that girl.
瑠奈讨厌那个人
She's all over Yamada and my brother.
老爱粘着山田和哥哥
I'll bet she's a tramp.
有种渣女的感觉
Oh my, Runa!
渣女？怎么会…
Where did you learn to talk like that?
你从哪里学会这个字？
It's always been the four of us.
我们明明一直是四人一起玩
Why do we have to add her now?
为什么现在必须要让她加入？
Whatever it takes,
瑠奈我…
I'm going to push her out of the guild.
一定会把那个人赶出公会
Since we're traveling the same way, let's go home together!
喂，我们方向一样，一起走吧
I managed to get that far,
我虽然忍不住趁势这么说
but conversation is at a standstill.
却完全聊不起来
-Say, Yamada… -Yeah?
-欸，山田 -什么事？
-Do you guys often get together like this? -Yeah.
-你们常常这样出来玩吗？ -是的
Wow, so you're all good friends!
是哦，感情真好耶
Yeah.
是啊
Now that you mention it…
对了
-Eita's a fun guy to know, huh? -Yeah.
-瑛太这个人好有趣哦 -是的
THE END
（结束）
-MY NEIGHBOR BUILT A FENCE, RECENTLY -YEAH?
我想想…
SNEAKING GLANCES
（偷瞄）
That hurt…
好痛…
Are you okay?
没事吧？
Sorry.
抱歉
You should change places with me.
你和我换位置吧
-That wouldn't be fair. -It's fine.
-不用啦，对你不好意思 -我没差
Thanks.
谢谢
So it was him.
是这边啊
I was a bit startled.
吓我一跳
I thought everyone was staring at me.
我还以为大家是在看我
THIS IS EMBARRASSING
（真丢脸…）
Well, I did find him strikingly handsome at first too.
我一开始也被他的帅脸吓到了
Do you like Yamada or something?
你喜欢山田吗？
Did it look that way to her?
外人看起来是这样吗？
This won't do!
不行！
Yamada's an important online gaming friend.
山田是重要的在线游戏伙伴
Oh, that reminds me. What will you eat for dinner?
对了，山田，你晚餐吃什么？
I'm not very hungry.
我现在没有很饿
Are you sure?
是吗？
Pudding, maybe?
大概吃布丁吧
ANOTHER ATTEMPT AT CONVERSATION
（再度开始挑战对话）
Come on!
什么啊
PUDDING
（软嫩布丁）
That'll be 128 yen!
总共是128圆
Thank you very much!
谢谢惠顾
Uh… you mean you were serious?
那个…你刚才是说认真的？
Yeah.
是的
-Do you live alone, Yamada? -Yeah.
-你是一个人住吗？ -是的
Do you cook for yourself?
你不会自己下厨吗？
Never.
完全不会
So what do you do for meals every day?
那你每天怎么解决三餐？
I just buy something from the convenience store.
买超商的东西随便吃
He's a high school student, isn't he?
山田是高中生没错吧？
Doesn't his mother have anything to say?
他妈妈都不会叮咛吗？
Well, I shouldn't ask about people's family lives.
但是管别人的家务事也不太好
Yamada!
山田
-Do you have a moment? -Yeah.
-可以稍微占用一点时间吗？ -可以
I only need 15, no ten minutes!
15分钟…不，10分钟就好
Just wait here for ten minutes! I'll be right back!
你在这里等我10分钟 我马上就回来
Ten minutes…
10分钟…
She seemed so upset just a while ago.
她原本明明那么伤心…
Yamada, it's been a while!
山田，好久不见
She sure does recover fast.
还真的振作得起来啊
Yamada!
山田
Sorry to keep you waiting!
让…让你久等了
Huh?
什么？
-Are you okay? -Wow…
-等等…你没事吧？ -糟糕
I haven't run like that since high school.
我高中之后就没狂奔过了…
What's all that stuff you're carrying?
这么大包东西…是什么啊？
This is… curry!
这个啊，是咖喱
You probably don't boil your own rice,
我想你八成也没在煮饭
so I brought some I kept frozen.
我也把冷冻白饭带来了
I made the curry this morning,
是我今早刚做好的咖喱
so it should last for two days.
大概可以吃个两天
I'm really short on money this month,
但我这个月有点拮据
so there's not much meat.
里面没放什么肉
But you can have
做为替代
the salad and pickled vegetables I bought at the convenience store.
给你刚在超商买的沙拉和福神酱菜
Wait, I…
不，那个…
I can't accept them.
怎么好意思？不用了
You're short on money, right?
而且你现在很穷吧
If you don't eat right,
不好好吃饭
you won't grow.
会长不大哦
Well, um…
是没错啦
Pudding is only for dessert!
布丁只是甜点哦
I know that, but…
的确是这样啦
Just consider it as looking out for a fellow guild member.
就当作是公会认识的缘分
But…
不过…
Your phone is ringing.
你的手机在响哦
Oh, it's mine?
啊，是我的啊
I wonder who it is.
会是谁啊？
Momo, maybe?
小桃吗？
Huh? It's an unknown number.
奇怪？是没看过的号码
Yes? Hello?
喂？你好
SMELLING THE CURRY…
（咖喱的味道…）
This is…
那个…
Runa.
我是瑠奈
Runa? Oh my, what is it?
瑠奈？怎么啦？
My brother gave me your number.
我向哥哥问了号码
Sorry to call, so suddenly.
冒昧打来，不好意思
It's totally fine!
没事的啦
You came all the way to meet us today.
你今天难得来一趟
I'm sorry I was so rude.
我却那么没礼貌，真抱歉
My brother told me to apologize.
哥哥也叫我向你道歉
It doesn't bother me at all.
我完全不在意啦
Everyone gets nervous meeting people for the first time.
有不认识的人在场都会紧张嘛
Anyway…
然后…
if you don't mind,
如果你愿意的话…
I'd like to hang out with you again.
我想再和你约出来玩
This time, I'd like to actually get to know you.
这次我想认真跟你做朋友
Runa…
瑠奈…
Sure!
嗯
Next Saturday, huh?
下星期六嘛
Sounds good.
嗯，没问题
Yeah!
嗯
I'm excited too!
我也好期待
Bye then!
再见咯
Runa wants to hang out with me!
我跟瑠奈约了要出去玩
Yeah, I overheard.
是的，我有听到
I thought for sure she didn't like me.
我还以为被她讨厌了
I'm glad.
所以我好开心
I wonder what her character is like in-game?
瑠奈在游戏里用什么角色呢？
-Do you know, Yamada? -A little.
-山田，你知道吗？ -知道一点
What class does she play?
她是用哪个职业？
I'll bet she's a mage.
果然是魔法师吗？
I'd like to see her character!
好想见一次看看哦
I wonder what her level is.
不知道她的等级多高？
Good for you.
真是太好了
Yeah. I'll add her number to my phone!
嗯，我要把她的号码存起来
She said Saturday, didn't she?
我记得她是说星期六吧
TUTORING RUNA SASAKI
（佐佐木瑠奈，家教打工）
"Tutoring Runa Sasaki."
佐佐木瑠奈，家教打工…
Right?
是这天吧
Maybe I heard wrong.
是我听错了吗？
Today, I'll introduce you to the avatars used by Princess Ruri!
今天要介绍瑠璃姬常换的装扮哦
PRINCESS RUI AVATAR COLLECTION
（瑠璃姬的服装系列）
First up is the "Alice with flowers and pocket watch" set!
首先是爱丽丝的花时钟套装
It's quite a popular avatar.
这是人气很高的装扮哦
I wear it once in a while!
人家偶尔会穿
Next is the "Priest's Sacred Robes, ultimate version."
接着是祭司的圣衣，极
If you remove the avatar, your armor will be exposed!
脱下之后防具会被看光光
Next is the "Red Rose for a Queen" set.
接着是献给女王的红玫瑰套装
It's gorgeous,
看起来十分华丽
but I don't wear it that often.
平常好像很少穿这套
Last but not least… my go-to!
最后是平时的招牌打扮
I love this one because it raises my attributes!
可以增强能力，我最爱了
Thanks for watching, everyone!
谢谢各位看到这里
Be sure to watch next week
有关瑠璃姬的情报
for more Princess Ruri info.
下周也敬请期…
-Got it? -Gross.
-待 -恶心